One specific use of the os module, and important
enough to warrant its own exam objective,
is the os.path submodule. Among its many uses,
os.path is used to see if a file exists in a
specific directory, as we are about to witness
with the following code example to analyze. This
code example may look familiar, as we used it
to see if a file did not exist, and then we
created a file if it did not exist and read it
if it did exist. In this version of the code,
this 613-ospath file, notice the import statement
on line 1. This import allows for any os module
to be used in this code. Since this code focuses
solely on file paths, it's good practice to limit
the import to only the os.path submodule, avoiding
wildcard imports that could clutter the namespace,
which is the set of names available in your
script for referencing objects. I will make
that change on line 1. When we import a library,
we should restrict the import to what is needed
so that one does not use a library module that
is not needed in the code and could disrupt the
original intent of the code. In addition to
checking to see if a file exists, we can use
os.path to see if a path exists to a directory and
possibly files within the directory. On line 15,
I will start a new variable, file_path, and set
it to an os.path.join and then, in parentheses,
a folder and a file. Join combines a folder,
subfolders, and a file into a single entity,
that can then be checked for existence. It
does this in an OS-agnostic manner, enabling
cross-platform code that works on any system
compatible with Python. On the next line, I will
add an if statement to see if this path on line
15 is a legitimate file path. We are simulating
if a configuration file for a game has already
been created in a specific folder. I will add
a print statement on line 17 to confirm that the
file exists. I will run the code. We do not get
a message that the file exists, so we would need
to create that file in a game sequence. Remember,
in addition to checking for file existence, you
can also use os.path to verify if a directory
exists. This is particularly useful when your
application requires certain directory structures.